kidscom.com 2009-12-12

# KidsCom - Privacy Policy

**KidsCom.com Privacy Policy**

KidsCom.com, launched in 1995, is the longest running online family-oriented community. Kids, parents and teachers from more than 202 countries around the world have joined us in our mission to give kids a voice to the world and to each other through a variety of engaging activities. We partner with other virtual worlds, gaming sites, content providers, consumer products companies and real world destinations to create one safe, educational and fun Virtual Universe.

Anyone can play on KidsCom.com. It is free and Idea Seeker or Ally registration is not required. Some areas of the site, however, are reserved for registered Idea Seeker Members and Allies who have obtained their parent's permission.

KidsCom.com follows the FTC guidelines for compliance with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act and Rule.

**Idea Seeker Registration**

**Who needs to register?**  
Registration is not required to play on and explore much of KidsCom.com. Registering as an Idea Seeker Member or Ally is only required for kids who want to chat on KidsCom.com, join the Find a KeyPal program, adopt and care for a Plant Baby, explore many areas of the Idea Seeker Universe and be included in other special activities and promotions. KidsCom.com does not require, as a condition of participation, any Idea Seeker Member or Ally to disclose more information than is reasonably necessary for them to participate in an activity. A premium membership is available. This paid membership provides kids and parents with even more content and activity access.

**What info is collected?**  
KidsCom.com is not permitted to collect more personal information than is reasonably necessary to permit a child to participate in activities on the site.

When a visitor to KidsCom.com wants to post something on the site (like on our monitored message boards or weekly creative writing challenges), we ask kids to provide info that is not personally identifiable (first name only, age and the country they live in). This information is included with their posted content and not used for any other purposes. All postings to KidsCom.com are screened by adult staff members before appearing on the site to help ensure children's online safety and privacy. Users are not allowed to post any personally identifiable information.

When a kid wants to become a registered Idea Seeker Member or Ally, we ask for the following information: 

  * Child's first name and screen name 
  * Child's date of birth 
  * Child's gender 
  * Child's country 
  * Parent or guardian's e-mail address 

This information is requested regardless of the age of the child. If kids would like to participate in KeyPal or Friend-to-Friend Messaging, it is required that they print out the registration form, have their parent or guardian sign it, and then mail or fax it to us as verification of parental consent to participate in these activities.

KidsCom.com uses this information to create and maintain separate Idea Seeker Ally and Member registration records for each child. E-mail addresses are used to communicate with Idea Seeker Members or Allies and their parents about activities on the site and other features. Date of birth, gender, city state, zip code and country are collected to help us develop the most appropriate content for our visitors.

We encourage parents to be involved with all of their child's online activities.

On the page where a kid or parent can update a kid's registration information, kids can voluntarily indicate how they learned of KidsCom.com by clicking one of seven choices: A friend, A parent, A search engine, A link from another site, A teacher, Surfing the Web, Some other way. We use this information to help guide our efforts to let more kids, parents and teachers know about KidsCom.com. Thy can also provide their city and state, which we use if we host real world events in specific locations. 

All personal information collected on KidsCom.com is done so directly from the parent or child. No personal information is collected from users through cookies or other passive means.

The KidsCom.com site may contain links to sites of sponsors and advertisers whose privacy policy and practices are different than our own. It is important for KidsCom.com visitors to always review a site's privacy policy before releasing any personal information. This includes content and promotions featured on the KidsCom.com site.

KidsCom.com uses every means available to safeguard the personal information of our Idea Seeker Members, Allies and site visitors, including a secure physical location and a protected electronic environment.

**What areas on KidsCom.com require Idea Seeker or Ally registration?**

**Idea Seeker Universe Chat** \- Kids can chat in the Idea Seeker Universe using our Keep it Safe, Keep it Clean Dictionary or pre-set phrases. KidsCom.com's staff of trained adult chat monitors reviews the chat to ensure that the rules are being followed. Private messaging between kids is not allowed. Idea Seeker Members or Allies are not permitted to share any information that will personally identify them. Idea Seeker Member or Ally registration is required to enable us to enforce the chat rules.

**Idea Seeker Plant Babies™** \- Registered kids can sprout and care for their very own Idea Seeker Plant Babies. Kids earn Virtual Points by playing certain educational games and fun activities on the KidsCom.com site. Kids then use their Virtual Points to take care of the needs of their Plant Babies. To allow kids of all ages to participate, different Plant Babies require different levels of skill, care and attention. Idea Seeker Plant Babies help kids fight the Darkness of Dumbness and the Clouds of Chaos. Idea Seeker Member or Ally registration is required for earning Virtual Points so we can accurately track each child's point totals.

**Find a KeyPal Program-** This program, popular with classroom teachers, allows kids to find electronic pen pals from around the world. Only kids with a parent's permission can participate in the program. When kids search for a KeyPal, they'll be given the first name, hometown and country of their KeyPal, plus an e-mail address and other fun facts kids have provided (such as favorite TV show or music group, hobbies, etc.). Kids can have as many KeyPals as they want, but this information is given out just one child at a time to prevent anyone from getting a large number of names at once. This is the only area on KidsCom.com where a child's e-mail address is allowed to be shared. We strongly encourage parents to responsibly monitor their child's e-mail activities. Idea Seeker Member or Ally registration is required to ensure that each child participating in KeyPal has parental permission.

**Friend-to-Friend Messaging-** Friend-to-Friend messaging allows Idea Seekers (paid members) to send private messages to other kids on their Friends List. Only Idea Seekers with a parent's permission can participate in this program. The messages can only include words from our Keep it Safe, Keep it Clean Dictionary, but we still strongly encourage parents to monitor their child's messages. Idea Seeker registration is required to ensure that each child has parental permission.

**Tell-A-Friend Messaging**

There are several places on KidsCom where kids can send an e-mail to a friend telling them about the site. The Tell-A-Friend form asks for the sender's first name and their friend's first name and e-mail address. The e-mail address is used only to send an e-mail with information about KidsCom to the friend. It is not stored by KidsCom or used for any other purpose.

**Does KidsCom.com share registration information?**

KidsCom.com is seeking out partners with content that offers families wholesome fun for their kids, as well as an opportunity to do good in the real world or to bring families together in play -- we call this group of kid-friendly sites the Idea Seeker Universe.

To make it easy for kids to visit all the sites, we will pass-through the registration information from our site to our partner sites. This allows kids to play within the Universe of sites without stopping to register at each site. It also gives them one username and password to remember to access all sites. All our partner sites are COPPA-compliant. The information we share with our partners is not the child's personally identifiable information. We will share:

  * User name 
  * Password 
  * Child's birthdate 
  * Child's gender 
  * Child's country 
  * Parent or guardian's e-mail address 

You can view the partners that are part of the Idea Seeker Universe here: <http://www.my.kidscom.com/jsp_a01_mkc/jsp_a01_b01_pb/planets.jsp>

**Does KidsCom.com use cookies?**

**What is a cookie?**  
A cookie is a small file that Web sites place on your computer to keep track of some information. On KidsCom.com, cookies do not store any personally identifiable information about you. You do not have to accept the cookies. In most cases, everything will work fine (just a little slower) if you do not accept the cookies. 

**Where are cookies used on Kidscom.com?**  
Cookies are used in two ways on KidsCom.com. KidsCom.com only uses cookies with registered Idea Seeker Members or Allies and does so only to improve the site functionality for registered Idea Seeker Members or Allies or where it is necessary to complete a particular activity. First, cookies are used to keep log-in information in some areas so that registered users can access the site faster. These cookies contain a unique ID number so you can get into areas faster, instead of waiting for our computer to sort through all the different people in our records. These cookies do not track any of your other online activities and do not contain any personally identifiable information. These cookies expire after a certain amount of time and delete themselves from your computer.  
Some of our advertisers may use cookies on our site. KidsCom.com requires those partners to be in full compliance with federal guidelines for children's online safety and privacy. Those cookies cannot be used to collect any personal information from our users.

**How can parents update and delete info?**  
Idea Seeker Members or Allies and parents can view, correct, update and delete personal information provided in the Idea Seeker registration process at any time. They will need the registered child's first name, screen name, date of birth and password. Visit the Idea Seeker registration update page at <http://www.kidscom.com/cgi-bin/registration/update.pl> for more information.

Parents can prevent further collection or use of their child's personal information by deleting that child's registration on the Idea Seeker registration update page at <http://www.kidscom.com/cgi-bin/registration/update.pl> or by unsubscribing the child from the Sarillion Monitor newsletter by following the directions contained in the newsletter. 

Parents of Idea Seekers (paid members) need to cancel the subscription before they delete a child's registration. Parents who have paid through PayPal should cancel through their PayPal account. Parents who paid by credit card should cancel by [contacting us](http://www.my.kidscom.com/jsp_a01_mkc/jsp_a01_b03_root_n_reward/contact.jsp).

**Who can parents contact if they have more questions?**   
If you have any additional questions or concerns about KidsCom.com, please contact the KidsCom.com staff. You can e-mail us at [staff@kidscom.com](mailto:staff@kidscom.com) or call us at 414.271.5437. 

**Acceptance of Privacy Policy**

This Privacy Policy outlines the information usage practices of KidsCom.com. By accessing, browsing or using this Web site or by submitting your personal information to KidsCom.com, you signify your agreement to the terms and conditions of this policy. If you do not agree to this policy, please do not submit your personal information to us. We reserve the right, at our discretion, to change, modify, add or remove portions of this Policy at any time. If at some point in the future, there is a material change to our information usage practices that affects your personal information, you will be notified of such change by a conspicuous posting on the Web site. Depending on the changes made, you may be unable to utilize a KidsCom.com service or Web site if you choose not to agree to a modification to this Privacy Policy. Your acceptance of a revised policy, which may be through an opt-in or opt-out mechanism following the effective date of any changes to this Privacy Policy shall mean that you have accepted those changes, subject to your continuing right to notify us at any time as to how you would like us to treat your personal information. 

KidsCom.com is published by Circle 1 Network. Our offices are at 131 West Seeboth Street, Milwaukee, Wisconsin, 53204.

Effective date: August 28, 2009
